Matthieu Bertrand

Novato, CA 94949 | 707-326-9528 | matthieubertrand5@yahoo.fr Github | Medium | Linkedin

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Previously an experienced manager in the restaurant industry, I enrolled with Flatiron School and learned about Ruby on Rails, JavaScript based programming and React. My experience of living and working in 3 countries gives me unique skills in cross-cultural collaboration. I am looking forward to bringing my knowledge and enthusiasm to a new company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby | Rails | SQL | Javascript (ES6) | React | Redux | Heroku | Postgres | HTML | CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Restaurant Style Github | Demo

Single Page Application showcasing the restaurants in my area by style

- Used Javascript, CSS and HTML to build the frontend
- Used Ruby on Rails to build the backend
- Async await functions to send fetch request to the backend API

California-Wineries Github | Demo

App where users can add wineries from California, their region and add reviews to wineries using Ruby on Rails

- Many-to-many relationships between users, wineries and regions
- Validations to protect the website from wrong data input from the clients
- Third party signup using Omniauth
- Include a class level ActiveRecord scope method

Wine-library - Github | Demo

Website where users can store edit and share their wines

- Built a MVC Sinatra Application
- Users have account where they can safely sign in and login using bcrypt
- Full CRUD actions in the controller with users only able to edit their own wines

Cocktail-list - Github | Demo

Cli Application displaying 25 cocktails starting with the letter 'A' with one level deep

- Provides access to data from a web page
- Client makes a choice of a cocktail then gets details about the cocktail

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Novato, California 11/2020 - present

Barrel House Tavern

Dining Room Manager / Bar Manager

Sausalito, California 11/2018 - 03/2020

- Built a team of 40 restaurant professionals providing the highest level of service for customers
- Increased sales by 20% in the 1st year, keeping all major costs below budget

Additional restaurant leadership responsibilities (global locations)

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Online
11/2020 - 04/2021

Lycee Lesdiguieres

Restaurant Management Degree

Grenoble, France 06/ 2010